Tevenn Lewis | Software Engineer

About Me

I am a full stack engineer, specializing in Javascript, ejs, express, mongoDB. I excel at collaborating with others in order to get the job done. With 4 years of experience in personal training and 1 year of experience in training management, I am accustomed to navigating tough situations on a regular basis researching and applying effective solutions. Currently, I am looking to apply my problem solving skills and incomparable work ethic to building web applications.

Skills

Languages - JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, SQL, Mongo, JSON, Typescript, EJS, DTL

Database - PostgreSQL, MongoDB | Other - RESTful Routing, JSON api

Libraries and Frameworks - React (class based and hooks), Express.js, Django, Jquery, Bootstrap, Semantic UI, Bulma, Object-Oriented Programming

Software Development Projects

June 2021 - PRESENT

<u>WeebsRUs</u> - Full-Stack application that allows users to watch current anime shows, recommend shows for other users, comment on videos as well as editing and deleting created comments.

- Used mongo db, express, and node to create a full stack application within a one week sprint.
- Incorporated EJS, jQuery, and the Bulma CSS framework to provide a complete viewer experience.
- Created an elevated and scalable code to manage new anime to be added to the database based on genre.
- (Collaboration bullet/ add)

<u>The-Wayfarer</u> - Full-Stack application that allows users to create a profile, login/logout, make comments on the nightlife in locations provided in the application as well as update and delete created comments.

- Used Postgres, Django, and Python to create a full stack application within a one week sprint.
- Took advantage of Postgres in order to create one to one and one to many relationships to create a more personalized user experience.
- Created multiple applications within the Django application for increased organization.
- (Collaboration bullet/ add)

<u>Train Like A Saiyan</u> - Full-Stack application that allows users to create a profile, login/ logout, create workouts based on preloaded exercises, update workouts and delete workouts.

- Used mongo db, express, and node to create a full stack application within a two week sprint.
- Utilized **mongo db** in order to create a many to many relationship between workouts and exercises to to provide a more streamlined user experience.
- Used Bulma CSS framework to create a consistent view throughout the application that adds the visual experience.

Professional Experience

United States Postal Service - City Carrier Assistant | Florin, CA

September 2020 - August 2021

- Delivered at least 50 packages and 4,000 pieces of mail under the allotted time; utilized extra time to assist other carriers.
- Sorted mail efficiently and ahead of schedule by spending time outside of work to learn the routes leaving more time for driving and delivery.

• Executed accurate deliveries daily to build rapport with my customers and leave my customers with a great delivery experience.

California Family Fitness - Assistant Fitness Manager | Folsom, CA

October 2019 - September 2020

- Promoted from personal trainer to assistant fitness manager (AFM) due to my consistently high sales, excellent customer service and experience with training.
- Produced more than \$18,000 in sales for January 2020 and was recognized as the top salesman for the month.
- Managed about 15 trainers per day; scheduled their clients based on their availability, helped close their sales after they pitched our training programs, checked in with their clients.
- Coached 10-15 clients per week in weight lifting, functional training and cardiovascular training.
- Made 50-60 cold calls per day to bring in new business resulting in hitting \$10,000 monthly sales goal.

Fit Republic - Head Coach/Head Trainer | Rancho Cordova, CA

December 2017 - June 2018

- Recorded the highest attendance rate in my high intensity interval training group classes with 15-20 people per class and 20 classes per week due to being the most popular trainer.
- Created more accessible workouts for clients who were incapable of typical high intensity interval training exercises, accommodating for injuries, physical and mental disabilities, and inexperience with training.
- Spearheaded a Saturday class geared towards the mental aspect of training and education about training concepts such as growth mindset, grit, nutrition and exercise physiology.

EDUCATION

General Assembly | Remote **Software Engineering Immersive**

September 2021

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

California State University Sacramento | Sacramento, CA Bachelor of Science in Kinesiology (B.S)

May 2021

National Academy of Sports Medicine | Sacramento, CA

Personal Trainer Certification